Marc-Adrian Polo

Accounting & Finance Associate

Motivated & detail oriented ACCA Level 1 qualified Accounting Associate with 8+ years experience in bookkeeping, payroll, tax services & preparation of financial statements. Seeking to utilise my skills & experience to further grow & learn in your organisation.

Personal Info

Address

14 Governor Plum

Santa Rosa Heights

Arima

Trinidad, West Indies

Phone

+1-868-293-5961

E-mail

marcadrianpolo@gmail.com

Date of birth

1987-09-29

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/marcadrianpolo

Skills

I.T. - A+ & Network +
Computer Support



Expert

Quickbooks



Expert

Sage/Sage 50

Quantum



Advanced

Microsoft Office -

Word, Excel &

Outlook



Google Suite/Google

Apps for Business



Advanced

Xero



Intermediate

Languages

English - IELTS 8.5/CLB 10



Native tongue

Experience

2017-09 - Accounting Officer

present ICSC Solutions Limited - Finance

- Reconcile Bank Accounts, General & Subledgers
- Prepare and process bi-monthly, monthly payroll
- Oversee Audit process and liaise with external auditors, external accountant
- Manage petty cash
- Oversee daily hand over of cash from cash sales
- Process daily data entry for Accounts Payable & Accounts Receivable
- Prepare landed costings

2016-11 - Accounting Assistant

2017-03

Exeqtech Limited - Finance

- Reconcile bank accounts & general ledger/AP subledger
- Prepare & tabulate monthly payroll
- Verify & scrutinize fortnightly payroll
- Liaise with vendors on payment schedules
- Prepare payment vouchers & cheques and forward for relevant signatures

2015-01 - Accounting Administrator

2016-11

International Products Limited - Finance

- Processing of all accounting data (AP, AR etc.)
- Prepare landed costings and costings on local products
- Prepare monthly management accounts
- Prepare & present quarterly management accounts at BoD Meetings
- Balance fleet inventory weekly & oversee warehouse stock counts
- Maintain schedules for prepayments & accruals
- Prepare & forecast expenditure & income
- Prepare all bank requests: wire transfers, drafts
- Liaise with auditors and prepare files for audit
- Prepare and remit all statutory payments
- Tabulate & remit payroll fortnightly & monthly
- Tabulate & verify commission for sales staff
- Manage petty cash
- Manage human resource: prepare and update employee contracts, leave, job letters & files, recruitment
- Reconcile bank accounts, general ledger to subledger & inventory
- Prepare & file annual returns and other administrative actions

2014-10 - Accounting Officer

2014-12 Metal Industries Company

2014-01 - Payroll Officer

2014-10 Eve Anderson Recruitment

Education

2012-01 - Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (ACCA)

present Level 1-Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (Via Exemptions):

Certified Accounting Technician (CAT) (2008 - 2010)

2008-01 - Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (ACCA) - Certified

Accounting Technician (CAT)

Certified Accounting Technician (CAT) (2008 - 2010)